Reid Collins

118 Greenpoint Ave., Apt. 2B · Brooklyn · New York · 11222 · 646-250-2869 · hi.hello.reid@gmail.com · hihelloreid.com

Programming Languages

Perl, Ruby, bash

Web Technologies

Perl w/ Catalyst, Ruby on Rails, Javascript (jQuery), HTML5/CSS3 (Bootstrap), AJAX, JSON, XML

Data Storage

MySQL, SQL*Loader, Postgres, BerkeleyDB, CDB

Deployment/Tools

Heroku, AWS (EC2 & S3), Git, Subversion, Puppet, tinydns, Bind, pound

Testing

Agile BDD/TDD with Cucumber and RSpec, Test::Unit

Overview

I am a skilled software developer that equally enjoys writing efficient code and interacting with clients/stakeholders to build a better product. I have extensive development experience in an open source Agile environment, processing large data volumes, implementing new web applications, and managing client accounts.

EXPERIENCE

Cheetahmail, An Experian Company DEC, 2011 to JUL, 2013 Software Developer, Development Team

- Implement new social media features in Cheetahmail's web application, allowing clients to synch email marketing campaigns with their Facebook, Pinterest, Twitter, and ShareThis accounts.
- Speed reporting of email marketing campaigns by utilizing SQL*Loader to load high volume ad click/transaction data files into the database. Critical feature for account teams to speed subsequent campaigns.
- Develop image rotation tool to accommodate holiday countdown images for Cheetahmail's numerous retail clients. Utilize Time::Local and POSIX modules to allow daily, weekly, or monthly image rotation.
- Liaise with QA engineers and Release teams to devise tests for software rollouts and fixed bugs when necessary. Assist in differentiating between code bugs and irregularities in virtual test environments.

Cheetahmail, An Experian Company FEB, 2008 to AUG, 2011 Software Developer, Client Development Team

- Design and implement remarketing campaigns for clients. Build automated import processes that parse client datafeeds from Coremetrics, Google Analytics, and Omniture to capture abandoned cart users, browsing customers, etc...
- Build automated process to convert customer's nightly inventory feeds from text or XML files into a usable CDB or BerkeleyDB. Contents of these databases could then be dynamically inserted into mailing content via Cheetahmail API.

Reid Collins

118 Greenpoint Ave., Apt. 2B · Brooklyn · New York · 11222 · 646-250-2869 · hi.hello.reid@gmail.com · hihelloreid.com

- Design automated report to measure attrition rate of client's subscriber lists. Compare client's incoming data files against bounced/unsubscribe addresses.
- Create automated scrubbing process, cleaning incoming data files against know spam traps, role addresses, and abuse addresses.
- Integration of client data imports/exports. Work closely with clients to design and implement customized solutions, aggregating performance metrics on a daily, weekly, monthly, or quarterly basis to synch with client or 3rd party database.
- Occasionally attend sales calls to explain complex technical/issues to prospective clients. Onboard new clients and assist with the integration of Cheetahmail's API suite.

Cheetahmail, An Experian Company JAN, 2005 to FEB, 2008 Software Engineer, Operations Team

- 24 x 7 application and systems support (rotating on-call schedule). Responsible for supporting 750+ clients. Coordinate emergency outage response/recovery teams. Work with client services and clients to address all application related issues in an expedient manner.
- Respond to bug reports, providing 1st, 2nd, and 3rd tier support to clients and client services. Provide bug fixes or alternative solutions for clients highly sensitive to revenue loss.
- Write one-off scripts to transform incoming client data into a usable format for the Cheetahmail database
- Write numerous scripts to automate daily tasks of the systems team (split files, cleanly terminate mailings, etc...)
- · Analyze and enhance queries for slow mailing campaigns segment counts
- Manage dns for 1200 domains delegated to Cheetahmail. Assist client's with configuration and help manage XML framework that centrally builds dns zone files for distribution across six name servers.

Cheetahmail, An Experian Company JAN, 2001 to FEB, 2005 Client Relationship Manager, Client Services Team

- Simultaneously manage 25+ clients from multiple verticals including catalog, financial, multi-channel retail, publishing, telecommunications, and travel.
- Manage production and strategy for top clients. Coordinate email marketing campaigns with client's other media (television, direct mail, web banner) initiatives.
- Enhance mailing content to bolster subscriber response, increasing click, open, and transaction rates.
- Help grow and maintain client subscriber lists by setting up registration forms, e-append, and viral marketing campaigns. Assist client in implementing Cheetahmail form coding to seamlessly capture data from client website.
- Attend sales calls with Cheetahmail sales team, demonstrating application to clients and fielding technical questions. Participate in contract renewals (100% retention rate)

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Tulane University, 05/1998

Major: International Relations